Guide to the Stanley Musgrove Papers Pertaining to Mae West
Department of Special Collections
Stanley Musgrove papers pertaining to Mae West
1948-1976
M1435
Musgrove, Stanley
1 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Correspondence, 1958-1974; movie scripts; newspaper clippings, 1948-1976; magazine articles about Mae West, 1969-1970; photographs; and press releases.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Theatre Collection, 2004. Accession 2004-143.
Biography / Administrative History
Stanley Musgrove was an old friend of Mae West. He was quick to say he was not her agent, but he was, or became, her publicist. He often "ran interference" for the star, screening her visitors, as well as admirers after her picture and autograph. He signed some of her correspondence and was privy to what her thoughts were on everything from her attendance at functions to what was appropriate regarding fees she received for appearances, interviews, and the like. He came to know many Hollywood personalities, from actors to directors. In 1982 he collaborated with George Eells on a biography of Mae West.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, 1958-1974; movie scripts; newspaper clippings, 1948-1976; magazine articles about Mae West, 1969-1970; photographs; and press releases.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
West, Mae
- Correspondence, 1950s-1960s1958-1969 (Othertype 1, Folder 1)
  Letters, cards, from various people regarding Mae West. and letters from Stanley Musgrove, publicist, on Mae West's behalf.
  Stanley Musgrove; Harriet Parsons
- Correspondence, 1970s1970-1974 (Othertype 1, Folder 2)
  Letters,notes, telegrams from varous people regarding Mae West and from Stanley Musgrove to various people on Mae West's behalf.
  Joseph Pasternak; Jet Fore; Robert Bruce; L. Ernest H. Katz; Richard Meryman; Arthur L. Wilde
- Correspondence, no dateNo date [1970s?] (Othertype 1, Folder 3)
  Letters, notes regarding Mae West from various peope and from Stanley Musgrove on Mae West's behalf.
  Mrs Joseph Schildkraut; Mark Spitz; Sam Coller.
- Invitation to "Sights and Sounds of Mae West"1970 August 20 (Othertype 1, Folder 4)
  Invitation from Gil Rodin
  MCA-Decca Records; Universal Studios
- Additional chapters to Mae West's biography[ 1970?] (Othertype 1, Folder 5)
  Copy of typescript of addtional material for Mae West's biography, "Goodness Had Nothing to Do With It."
  George Cukor; Robert Wise; Stanley Musgrove; Dr. Norman Topping
- Typescript, Mae West reads bedtime stories[ late 1960s?] (Othertype 1, Folder 6)
  Bedtime stories and fairy tales
- Typescript, "The Drag"1968 (Othertype 1, Folder 7)
  Proposed movie script
- Script, "Myra Breckinridge"1969 (Othertype 1, Folder 8)
  Movie script
- Script, "Diamond Lil"1970 (Othertype 1, Folder 9)
- Script, "Sexette"1970 (Othertype 1, Folder 10)
- New-Clear Universal Foundation1973 (Othertype 1, Folder 11)
  Endorsements of New-Clear Foundation. Photos of: Mae West, Ralph Campo, Gary Rampa.
- Miscellaneous: airline ticket, Stage Door magazine release, gangsters in films--James Cagney, Paul Munino date (Othertype 1, Folder 12)
- Newspaper clippings and Variety broadsheet1948 (Othertype 2, Folder 1)
  About Mae West
- Newspaper clippings1956 (Othertype 2, Folder 2)
- Newspaper clippings1968 (Othertype 2, Folder 3)
- Newspaper clippings1969 (Othertype 2, Folder 4)
- Newspaper clippings1970 (Othertype 2, Folder 5)
- Newspaper clippings1971 (Othertype 2, Folder 6)
- Newspaper clippings1972 (Othertype 2, Folder 7)
- Newspaper clippings1973 (Othertype 2, Folder 8)
- Newspaper clippings1974 (Othertype 2, Folder 9)
- Newspaper clippings1975 (Othertype 2, Folder 10)
- Newspaper clippings1976 (Othertype 2, Folder 11)
- Newspaper clippingsn.d. (Othertype 2, Folder 12)
- West magazine1969 Dec. (Othertype 2, Folder 13)
  Magazine article about Mae West
- Life magazine1969 Apr. (Othertype 2, Folder 14)
- Scene Magazine1970 June (Othertype 2, Folder 15)
- Close Up Magazine1970 July 9 & 30 (Othertype 2, Folder 16)
  Magaztne articles about Mae West and Raquel Welch
- TV Guide1970 Aug. (Othertype 2, Folder 17)
- "Mae West Raps," unnamed magazinen.d. (Othertype 2, Folder 18)
  Interview with Mae West
- Radio columns "Rona Reports"1970 Jan. - Sept. & Nov 1973 (Othertype 2, Folder 19)
  Mention of Mae West and controversy over "Myra Breckinridge" in which Mae West starred
  Cary Grant; John Lennon; Raquel Welch; Jack Valenti; Perry Como; President Nixon; Cary Grant; John Lennon; Raquel Welch; Perry Como; Richard Harris; Jack Valenti; Richard Zanuck; Oudini; Rick Jagger.
- Photographs of Mae WestVarious dates (Othertype 2, Folder 20)
- Press releases [1970?] (Othertype 2, Folder 21)